Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V. Personal Files, 1921-2012; 50.39 Linear Feet in 39 manuscript boxes, 17 record cartons, 3 flat boxes, 1 tall LP box, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 2 flat-file folders.; 24.725 Gigabytes in 1,245 digital files.
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Frank Kofsky and Bill Dixon Interview, September -November, 1966; cuid38966
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interview by Robert Levin - Jazz and Pop, 1970; cuid38967
    - Audio (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1464)
    - Electronic Records
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Interview of Bill Dixon, Avant Garde, Robert Levin -- Compilation Tape, circa 1970s; cuid38852 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1468)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Diana Chingos Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, 1970s-1980s; cuid40254 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Written Response to Bill Dixon Interview with John Tchicai, May 1971; cuid40255 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Paul Levi Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, April 1972; cuid40256 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Robert Sawyer Interview with Bill Dixon at Bennington College, December 13-14, 1972; cuid38853 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2333, Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1420, Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2061)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, May 15, 1975; cuid40257 (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Gail Parker on Bill Dixon, circa 1975-1980; cuid40258 (Box 71, Half inch video reel 481_1787)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon, Raccords, October 8, 1976; cuid38854 (Box 68, U-matic 481_934)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Nadia Quamar, Putney, Vermont, April 21, 1978; cuid38856 (Box 68, U-matic 481_940)
    Duration: 21 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Art Brooks, Ensemble 5, Putney, Vermont, April 21, 1978; cuid38857 (Box 68, U-matic 481_941)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Niccola Tessitore Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, 1980; cuid40259 (Box 202, Folder 5)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Documentary: Imagine the Sound by Ron Mann -- Publicity, Poster, Correspondence Re: Interview, 1980-1981; cuid40260 (Box 204, Folder 15, Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bob Rusch Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, Edited Drafts, 1982; cuid40261 (Box 202, Folder 7)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon Concert, Tape 3, 1983; cuid38858 (Box 68, U-matic 481_003)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon Interview Dubs, 1983; cuid38859
    - Video -- 1 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_931)
    - Video -- 2 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_939)
    - Video -- 3 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_943)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon Concert, 1983; cuid38860 (Box 68, U-matic 481_942)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon Interviews, circa 1983; cuid38861
    - Video -- 1 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_932)
    - Video -- 2 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_933)
    - Video -- 3 of 3 (Box 68, U-matic 481_938)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project: Bill Dixon Interview, circa 1983; cuid38862 (Box 76, Betacam 481_2353)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Film: Bill Dixon: A Personal Portrait, circa 1983
    - Video -- 1 of 5 (Box 72, Vhs 481_1767)
    - Video -- 2 of 5 (Box 67, Vhs 481_018)
    - Video -- 3 of 5 (Box 73, Vhs 481_1768)
    - Video -- 4 of 5 (Box 73, U-matic 481_1769)
    - Video -- 5 of 5, cuid38863 (Box 77, U-matic 481_1766)
      Duration: 25 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Film: Bill Dixon: A Personal Portrait -- Notecards / Notes for Interview, circa 1983; cuid40262 (Box 202, Folder 8)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interviewed at Bennington College, circa 1983; cuid38864 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1773)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project -- Bill Dixon Various Images (Dub), October, 1983; cuid38865 (Box 68, U-matic 481_946)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project --Various Images with Horn, Hands, Music, Records, Portraits, October, 1983; cuid38866 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1776)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project --Bill Dixon Interview (Master), October, 1983; cuid38867
    - Video -- 1 of 4 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1782)
    - Video -- 2 of 4 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1779)
    - Video -- 3 of 4 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1778)
    - Video -- 4 of 4 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1771)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project --Bill Dixon Concert at Bennington College (Dub), October 27, 1983; cuid38868
    - Video -- 1 of 5 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1775)
    - Video -- 2 of 5 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1777)
    - Video -- 3 of 5 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1774)
    - Video -- 4 of 5 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1772)
    - Video -- 5 of 5 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1770)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project --Bill Dixon Concert at Bennington College (Master), October 27, 1983; cuid38869 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1780)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project --Bill Dixon Concert (Dub), October 27, 1983; cuid38870 (Box 72, U-matic 481_1781)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Jesse Katz Interview with Bill Dixon for Tool and Die -- Publication, Notes, Drafts, 1984; cuid40263 (Box 202, Folder 9)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Brian Auerbach and Thomas Miessgang Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, June 22, 1985; cuid40264 (Box 202, Folder 10)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Dissertation: Black Professional Musicians in Higher Education... by Christopher Hardin, 1987; cuid40265 (Box 202, Folder 11)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Talks with Quinn Johnson and Chris Bakriges, 1993; cuid38871 (Box 67, Vhs 481_023)
    Duration: 47 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Interview, December 5, 1993; cuid38872
    Duration: 214 minutes (in two parts)
    - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_015)
    - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_016)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Correspondence, Transcript, and Thesis: The October Revolution in Jazz: Critical Reception of the "New Thing" by Christopher G. Bakriges, May 1995, 1996; cuid40266 (Box 202, Folder 12, Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Christian Broecking Interview with Bill Dixon for Article: Closed Circle of Unconsciousness -- Transcript, July / August 1995; cuid40267 (Box 202, Folder 13)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Iain Anderson Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, 1995-1996; cuid40268 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- October Revolution Profile, 1999; cuid38873 (Box 47, Audiocassette 481_2761, 481_2762)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Dixon Interview Conducted by Michael Lucio Sternbach and Aaron Messelaar (for Down to the Crux?), circa 2000; cuid38874 (Box 67, Vhs 481_025)
    Duration: 164 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Documentary -- Down to the Crux (Rough Cut) by Michael Lucio Sternbach, circa 2000; cuid38875 (Box 67, Vhs 481_019)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Documentary -- Down to the Crux (Final Cut) by Michael Lucio Sternbach, circa 2000; cuid38876 (Box 67, Vhs 481_033)
    Duration: 45 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Frank Rubolino Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript and Related, 2002; cuid40269 (Box 203, Folder 3)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Patrick Hargon Questions and Bill Dixon Answers Re: Musicians and New Jazz in the 1960s, 2003; cuid40270 (Box 203, Folder 4)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Thesis: "This is American Music": Aesthetics, Music and Visual Art of Bill Dixon by Andrew Rraffo Dewar, April 2004; cuid40271 (Box 203, Folder 5)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Thesis: …So We Did It Ourselves: A Social and Musical History of Musician-Organized Jazz Festivals from 1960 to 1973 by Michael Heller, May 19, 2005; cuid40272 (Box 203, Folder 6)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Dissertation and Interview Transcript: Testing, Testing... by Benjamin Piekut -- Re: Jazz Composers' Guild, 2006-2008; cuid40273 (Box 203, Folder 7, Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interview with Phil Freeman, April 27, 2008; cuid38968
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon's Conversation with Marc Medwin, circa 2009; cuid40327
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Answers Written by Bill Dixon to Questions Sent by Franck Médioni Re: Coltrane, April 14, 2009; cuid40274 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project -- Bill Dixon (Cutaways) 1, 1A, Undated; cuid38877 (Box 68, U-matic 481_945)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Steven Albahari Project -- Bill Dixon Performance, Undated; cuid38878
    Duration: 73 minutes (in four parts)
    - Video -- 1 of 4 (Box 68, U-matic 481_935)
    - Video -- 2 of 4 (Box 68, U-matic 481_936)
    - Video -- 3 of 4 (Box 68, U-matic 481_937)
    - Video -- 4 of 4 (Box 68, U-matic 481_944)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interview (Rough Cut), Undated; cuid38879 (Box 76, U-matic 481_2362)
  - interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interview, Undated; cuid38991 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1118)
    Duration: 99 minutes
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Interview, Undated; cuid38992 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1129)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon and Lewis Conversation, Undated; cuid38969
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Bill Dixon Profile, Undated; cuid38881 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1487, 481_1496)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Conversation with Bill Dixon and William II, Satie Piano Music, Undated; cuid38882 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2344)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Conversation: CCN, Undated; cuid38883 (Box 67, Vhs 481_017)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Conversations and Excerpts, Undated; cuid38884 (Box 67, Vhs 481_024)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Dixon Project: Interview and Work, Undated; cuid38970
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- John O'Brien, Chicago Today, Undated; cuid38885 (Box 59, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2073)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Madison Radio Interview with Lynda Clauder, Trumpet Solos, Undated; cuid38886 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1284)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Various Out-Takes, Undated; cuid38887
    - Audio (Box 14, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1101)
    - Film, cuid41209 (Box 65, Super 8mm film reel 481_1046)
      Color reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Some perforation damage.
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Unknown Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, Undated; cuid40275 (Box 204, Folder 3)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Jazz Trumpeters Questionnaire / Bill Dixon Answers, Undated; cuid40276 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - Interviews and Scholarly Works -- Unknown Interview with Bill Dixon -- Transcript, Undated; cuid40277 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: L'Opera; The Work of Bill Dixon; Classes and Lectures; "Index" (1965); "Wisc" (1972); "Thoughts" (1986); "Letters"; "Round Up the Usual Suspects"; "Thoughts" (1987), 1965-1994; cuid38888 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1136)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Ellington Class 1994, University of the Streets 1967, Orchestra Work, Ensemble, 1967-1994; cuid38988
    - Papers (Box 213, Folder 12)
    - Video (Box 70, Vhs 481_1123)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Steven Albahari, Friedman, Moore Retirement, Fahlin, Wesleyan, Andy Grossman, circa 1983; cuid38889 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1108)
    Duration: 107 minutes
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Velvet Hope Clark Dance; Jack Moore Retirement Piece; SVC Performance, 1990; Furth, 1990; L'Opera, cuid38890 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1141)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Ellington Class, 1994; Retirement Lecture, 1995; Dances by Andy Grossman; Recording of "Thoughts"; Dance by Jack Moore with Dixon on Piano, 1994-1995; cuid38985
    - Papers (Box 213, Folder 13)
    - Video (Box 67, Vhs 481_1145)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Steven Albahari Film, Jack Moore Retirement Piece, 3 Days in October at Bennington College, Bill Dixon Directing Ensemble, Undated; cuid38891 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1132)
    Duration: 252 minutes
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Steven Albahari; "Dewhorse"; "Summerdance"; "Imagine the Sound" Part I, Undated; cuid38892 (Box 67, Vhs 481_1149)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Ensemble Lecture Bennington College, Talk with Quinn Johnson, Villeurbanne Concert, URDLA Show, Villeurbanne Master Class, Undated; cuid38893 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1131)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Ensemble; Talks; "Explanation"; Presentation, Lecture, and Performance, Undated; cuid38894 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1143)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Köln, SVC, Duet with A. Grossman, Duet with David Bindman, Jack Moore Retirement Piece, Jerusalem Workshop, Cecil Taylor Duet in Vienna, Undated; cuid38895 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1122)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Lecture, SVC Performance, Dance Performance, Tenor Saxophone and Piano, Jack Moore Piece, "Letters" Excerpt, Villeurbanne France, 3 Days in October, Undated; cuid38896 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1133)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Panel on Music for Dance, 1987; Chivas Sandage's "Rushing at the Shift"; M. R. Ellenhorn's "A Field Called No Time", Undated; cuid38897 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1138)
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Suspects; Jack Moore Piece, Undated; cuid38898 (Box 67, Vhs 481_1144)
    Duration: 132 minutes
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: Suspects; SVC; Jim Piece; Piano and Tenor; Jerusalem; Berlin, Undated; cuid38899 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1142)
    Duration: 95 minutes
  - Bill Dixon Video Excerpts: SVC; Talk in Villeurbanne; Villeurbanne Concert; Book Exhibit; Rehearsal for Sisyphus II (B.C.); Solo - 2nd Part of Faculty Presentations, Undated; cuid38900 (Box 67, Vhs 481_1146)
  - Bill Dixon Telephone Conversation with Arthur Doyle, 1970; cuid38971
  - Son, William II and William Sr. Work, February 8, 1970; cuid38907 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2232)
  - Home Movies, 1971, Undated
    - Curling hair, Undated
      - Magnetic soundtrack, cuid41234 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1043)
        Magnetic soundtrack synced to picture access files; see reel 481_1044.
      - Color positive, cuid41235 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1044)
        Preservation note: Badly dye faded -- print is red throughout; Magnetic soundtrack synced to picture for access files.
    - Dark indoor scene, Undated; cuid41232 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1040)
      Black and white reversal; Silent.
    - Son, William II -- On the Slides, circa July, 1971; cuid38908 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_981)
    - Son, William II -- On the Slides, circa July, 1971; cuid41210 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_982)
    - Son, William II -- At home and in the city, Undated; cuid41213 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_1034)
      Donor permission is required for access. Please contact NYU Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
    - Son, William II -- At School, Undated; cuid38911 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_999)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Some perforation damage close to the head.
    - Boat ride, park scenes, Undated; cuid41230 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_993)
    - Boat ride, park scenes, Undated; cuid41227 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_990)
      Black and white negative; Silent; Preservation note: In 2025, this film was sent to Film Rescue for processing. It was likely shot on reversal. Film Rescue processed the camera film as a negative.
    - Son, William II -- Miscellaneous, Apartment, Interiors, Trip around Manhattan, Undated; cuid38913 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_983)
    - Son, William II -- On Bicycle, Undated; cuid38912 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_984)
      Black and white negative; Silent.
    - Son, William II -- Park scenes, Undated; cuid41211 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_988)
    - Son, William II -- Park scenes, Undated; cuid41212 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_994)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Somewhat dirty near head.
    - Park scenes, Undated; cuid41226 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_989)
    - Park scenes, Undated; cuid41228 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_991)
    - Playing at the park, Undated; cuid41229 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_992)
    - Son, William II -- Playground, Undated; cuid41215 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1039)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Film had water damage and was sent to a lab for cleaning and repair. This reel consists of several rolls spliced together.
    - Son, William II -- Playground, Undated; cuid38909 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_987)
    - Son, William II -- Playground, Undated; cuid38910 (Box Shared Fales 119, 16mm film reels 481_1033)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Occasional holes in film, some scratches along perforations.
    - Son, William II -- Playground, Undated; cuid41216 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1041)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Film orientation changes at splice close to tails.
    - Street and playground scenes, Undated; cuid41221 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_997)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: In 2025, this film was sent to Film Rescue for processing. Per the original box, the Kodachrome II color film should have been processed by October 1970. The film was processed in 2025 as black and white negative. On inspection, the perforations were exposed while they were out of alignment. It's possible that the film was double exposed, possibly once with the lens cap on. A few black frames were removed from the end of the film.
    - Street and playground scenes, Undated; cuid41223 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_1036)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Sprocket damage.
    - Street and playground scenes, basketball, Undated; cuid41231 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1038)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Perforation damage close to the head, some scratches along perforation lines.
    - Son, William II -- Trip around Manhattan, Undated; cuid38914 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_995)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation note: Long lateral base scratch in perforation area in first half.
    - Son, William II -- Waterfront, park, and dentist scenes, Undated; cuid41214 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_1035)
      Black and white reversal; Silent; Preservation Note: Mixed orientation of film and perforation numbers spliced together.
    - Woman dancing, Undated; cuid41233 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_1042)
  - Pink Panther Film Project, Madison, 1971-1972; cuid38901 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1112)
  - Poems and Dedications to Bill Dixon, 1973-1976, Undated; cuid40278 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Address Books and Mailing Lists, 1974, Undated; cuid40279 (Box 204, Folder 7-11)
  - Custody Documentation for Son, William II, 1975; cuid40280 (Box 204, Folder 12)
  - Birthday Cards (50th and Unknown) and Artwork in Honor of, 1975, Undated; cuid40315 (Box 210, Folder 14, Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Reproduced Bill Dixon Journal Entries, circa 1975; cuid40281 (Box 204, Folder 13)
  - Documentation Re: Stolen Stereo Equipment, 1977-1979; cuid40282 (Box 204, Folder 14)
  - Black Music Interviews - Nadi Qamar, circa 1978; cuid38902 (Box 77, U-matic 481_1755)
  - Black Music Interviews - Marta Stevens, George Barrow, December 1, 1978; cuid38903 (Box 73, U-matic 481_1756)
  - Written Account of Racial Phone Call Harassment, 1980; cuid40283 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Entry for Bill Dixon in Who's Who in America, 1981, 1996; cuid40284 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Italian Language Courses -- Tests, Lessons, etc., 1981-1998; cuid40285 (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - Quotes by Bill Dixon (for Various Publications), circa 1982-1986; cuid40286 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - Documentation Re: Traffic Ticket, 1983; cuid40287 (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - Documentation Re: Issues with Landlady, 1983-1986; cuid40288 (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - BMI Jazz Pioneer Award -- Letters, Award, 1984-1985; cuid40289 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Dixon Timelines, Recollections, Notes Re: Career, circa 1985-2006; cuid40290 (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Conversation with a Young Woman, 1986-1987; cuid38904 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_198)
  - Bill Dixon Talks with a Young Woman, circa 1987; cuid38972
  - National Endowment for the Arts -- Documentation Re: Serving on the Music Committee, 1990; cuid40291 (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Holiday and Notecards Created with Dixon's Artwork and Photographs, 1990-2006; cuid40292 (Box 205, Folder 10-11)
  - Patent and Trademark of "Bill Dixon" Documentation, 1992-1993; cuid40293 (Box 205, Folder 12)
  - Bill Dixon, Inc. Corporation -- Correspondence, Documentation for Establishment, 1992-1994; cuid40294 (Box 205, Folder 13)
  - Diary Entry, September 7, 1994; cuid40295 (Box 205, Folder 14)
  - Income and Expenses Lists, 1995-1997; cuid40296 (Box 205, Folder 15)
  - Documentation Re: Dispute with Honda Car Dealer, 1996; cuid40297 (Box 205, Folder 16)
  - Documentation Re: Alain Kirill Unauthorized Use of Dixon Name, circa 1997; cuid40298 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Dixonia Book -- Reviews, Updated Drafts by Ben Young, 1998, 2009; cuid40299 (Box 206, Folder 2-3)
  - Bill Dixon Promotional Packets / Portfolio, circa 1990s, circa 2002, 2006; cuid40300 (Box 206, Folder 4-6, Box 170, Folder 16)
  - Presentation -- Andrew Ruffo Dewar on Bill Dixon, 2003; cuid38984
  - Bill Dixon Website Pages (Printed Out), 2004, 2010; cuid40301 (Box 206, Folder 7-8)
  - Artwork of Bill Dixon and George Lewis, by Jeff Sculanger, 2006; cuid40316 (Box 210, Folder 15)
  - Bill Dixon Record Review, Hear and Now, 2008, cuid38973
  - Bill Dixon Photograph Calendar, 2009; cuid40302 (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Bill Dixon Memorial Service at St. Mark's Church, New York, July 31, 2010; cuid38974
  - Bill Dixon Memorial Service Program, Obituary, Sympathy Cards, 2010; cuid40303 (Box 206, Folder 10)
  - Presentation -- Ben Young on Bill Dixon, 2011; cuid38981
  - Bill Dixon Practicing Italian, Undated; cuid38905 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1478)
  - Telephone Conversations, Undated; cuid38906 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_182)
  - Bill Dixon Autobiography Work Files, Undated; cuid40304 (Box 207, Folder 1-4)
  - Sketch of Bill Dixon Playing Trumpet, by "Franz", Undated; cuid40305 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Bill Dixon Professional Stationary, Envelopes, Business Cards, Logo, Brochure, Undated; cuid40306 (Box 207, Folder 6)